Shubham Srivastava

(416) 676 9108 srivastava.shubham@outlook.com Toronto, ON LinkedIn

A marketing professional with an MBA and 8+ years of diverse industry experience (E-Commerce, Healthcare, Technology and Retail). Skilled in Product Marketing, Research, Go-to-Market, Positioning, Branding, Digital Marketing, Marketing Automation, Demand Generation and Sales Enablement

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

INCA'S GOLD Marketing Specialist - Toronto

Sep 2020 - Present

Industry: Food & Retail – B2B and B2C. Role: Digital Marketing, Strategy, Account Management.

- Researched, applied, and successfully secured the Women Business Enterprises (WBE), Canada certification for the organization
- Analyzed, benchmarked and improved the products listing; established the procedures for maintaining and reporting inventory, sales, and earnings on Amazon.ca
- Studied market and competition, entailing to **identification of 2 new products** to be included in the products portfolio, establishing the network for the final product development and procurement
- Leading the market research in collaboration with **BDC**, aimed at retail and international market launch
- Managing the two biggest customer accounts contributing to more than 60% of the total revenue

Senior Marketing Manager – New Products – India Oct. 2018 – Feb. 2020 Amplus Solar, PETRONAS Industry: Consumer Durables - B2C. Role: Product Marketing, Go-to-Market, Digital and Channel Marketing, BTL, Sales Enablement.

- Led the ideation, market research, and prototyping of Residential Solar Products; introduced Atrium the first of its kind Solar Pergola in India
- Established the positioning for products and HomeScape, drove the messaging and content, developed the annual brand plan, managed marketing agencies
- Strategized the GTM, drove the launch and marketing, led demand generation generated 7500+ leads through digital marketing and 1500+ leads through BTL and channel marketing
- Developed sales enablement tools for sales team and channel partners: Presentations, Brochures, Templates, Videos, Case Studies, Sales Kit; Established KPIs and sales SOPs
- Planned and organized Channel Partner meets, webinars, trainings; represented HomeScape in tradeshows

VP - Product Marketing - India ParallelStack Systems Jun. 2017 – Jun. 2018

Industry: SaaS – B2B. Role: Product Marketing, Go-to-Market, CRM, Lead Generation, Sales Enablement.

- Researched and Strategized Go-to-Market; Led the Product Launch and Marketing to drive demand
- Led **product demo** sessions, **organized** multiple **webinars** and represented organization in networking events
- Created the Buyer Journey Framework; Evaluated, implemented, and managed CRM (Zoho), marketing automation (Marketo), customer support; developed multiple Sales Enablement tools
- Digital Marketing: Designed and managed Google Search, LinkedIn ads, executed A/B and Multivariate testing; conducted, participated and represented the organization in webinars
- Cross-functional collaboration with internal and external teams, engaged stakeholders, conducted competitive analysis, identified gaps and needs, and defined the product roadmap

Industry: Healthcare Technology – B2B and B2C. Role: Product Management, Marketing, Sales Enablement

- Best of the Bump (the flagship product) was selected among top 15 applications globally to the Miller Center for Social Entrepreneurship's Global Social Benefit Institute (GSBI) ninth Online Cohort
- Built a team of 9 and managed 5 products (2 websites and 3 mobile apps) from ideation, market research, requirement documents to **GTM**, launch, demand generation, marketing, engagement, and growth
- Developed cohesive product marketing strategy across product lines to drive adoption and usage of the products; established success criteria for all marketing initiatives and evaluated overall ROI for all programs
- Marketing Automation and Digital Marketing: SEO and SEM, Email Marketing, Social Media Marketing and Content Strategy and Marketing

CoCreate 3D	Co-Founder – India	Jun. 2013 – Apr. 2015		
Industry: Technology - B2B and B2C. Role: Product Management, Digital Marketing, Business Development,				
Investors Relation				

- Incubated and mentored at the Indian School of Entrepreneurship (iSEED), Gurugram
- Organized multiple workshops on 3D printing, educated and raised awareness among 2000+ potential users and witnessed 250+ registrations
- **Digital Marketing**: Electronic Direct Mails, Social Media generated 400+ inquiries and 60+ sale orders

Flareum Technologies	Manager – Sales & Marketing – India	Apr. 2012 - May 2013		
Industry: Consumer Durables – B2B. Role: Marketing, Account Management, Business Development				

- Awarded with Certificate of Excellence for exceeding my targets and model performance
- Built the portfolio of key accounts consulted and delivered highly customized solar energy solutions
- Maintained a strong sales pipeline through relationship building, account management and lead generation,
 thereby achieving direct and network sales of INR 20.5 million exceeding the target by INR 5.5 million

Standard Chartered Bank	Summer Intern – India	Apr. 2011 – May 2011		
Industry: Banking – B2C. Role: Marketing and Strategy				

 Conducted primary and secondary market research entailing analysis of the data obtained from personal interviews, offline surveys and recommended expansion in products, services and product features

Education				
MBA	Indian Institute of Management (IIM) Rohtak, India Jun. 2010 – Mar.			
B.Tech.	Institute of Engineering & Technology, Lucknow, India	Aug. 2005 – Jun. 2009		
Tools, Skills & Certifications				
CRM	Adwords - Search and Display Certification	Account Management		
Wordpress	Google Analytics Individual Qualification	Zoho, Hubspot, Marketo		
Product Roadmap	Cross-Functional Collaboration	SEO, SEM, Email Marketing		